<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN"
    "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % sharedents SYSTEM "shared-entities.xml" >
%sharedents;
]>
<chapter id="configuration">
  <info>
    <author>
      <firstname>Owen</firstname>
      <surname>Synge</surname>
    </author>
  </info>  
  <section id="Environment Variables.">
    <title>Environment Variables.</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>HOME Used as a prefix for configuration files and certificates.</listitem>
      <listitem>VMCASTER_KEY Path to the private key for the signing of image lists.</listitem>
      <listitem>VMCASTER_CERT Path to the certificate for the signing of image lists.</listitem>
      <listitem>VMCASTER_CFG Path to the configuration file for vmcaster.</listitem>
      <listitem>VMCASTER_RDBMS SQLite based connection string, This defaults to 'sqlite:///vmcaster.db'.
This URL refers to the current working directory, to use an absolute path with 
SQLite, add an extra slash to the URL like syntax.</listitem>
      <listitem>VMCASTER_LOG_CONF vmcaster uses pythons standard logging module, this sets the configuration file 
to be used for logging. For specifications on how to set this up see the python
logging documentation.</listitem>
      <listitem>VMCASTER_X509_DIR Sets the default directory for the users x.509 certificates. If not set this 
value is defaulted to "$HOME/.globus".</listitem>
      <listitem>VMCASTER_X509_KEY Sets the default path for the users x.509 user key. If not set this 
value is defaulted to "$HOME/.globus/userkey.pem".</listitem>
      <listitem>VMCASTER_X509_CERT Sets the default path for the users x.509 user key. If not set this 
value is defaulted to "$HOME/.globus/usercert.pem".</listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <title>Configuration</title>
    <section id="Deployment">
    <title>Deployment</title>
    <para>It is wise to deploy an "image list subscriber" so you can check for errors with 
vmcaster as your "image list" publisher. vmcatcher 
(http://github.com/hepix-virtualisation/vmcatcher) is an "image list subscriber" 
that has almost the same dependencies as vmcatcher.</para>
    <section id="DeploymentSecurityNote">
      <title>Security note</title>
      <para>It is more secure to use "https" than "http" for serving the image list. While 
the authenticity of the image list is secured by the image list signature, the 
signature cannot prevent "man in the middle" presenting an old signed image list.</para>
      <para>For serving images http is as secure as https, as the authenticity of the image 
is secured by the image list's signature, thus the worst a man in the middle 
attack can do with images is provide a denial of service when the image does not 
match the sha512 hash it will be detected and rejected.</para>
      <para>It is expected future versions of vmcatcher will issue a warning when 
subscribing to and retrieving image lists from unauthenticated hosts. Image list 
subscribers will prefer not to see these warnings, and may decide to only trust
image lists hosted on authenticated servers.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
</chapter>
