<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN"
    "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % sharedents SYSTEM "shared-entities.xml" >
%sharedents;
]>
<chapter id="introduction">
  <info>
    <author>
      <firstname>Owen</firstname>
      <surname>Synge</surname>
    </author>
  </info>
  <title>Introduction</title>
  <section id="organisation-fedc-intro-intro">
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>Vmcaster is a simple tool for managing and updating your published 
virtual machines image lists. Following the HEPiX image list format.</para>    
    <para>vmcaster software is available here:</para>
    <para>https://github.com/hepix-virtualisation/vmcaster</para>
    <para>Users of this application should read "security-related policy requirements for 
the generation and endorsement of trusted virtual machine (VM) images for use on 
the Grid". The URL is shown below.</para>
    <para>https://edms.cern.ch/document/1080777</para>
    <para>This tool is designed to aid "endorsers" as defined in the security policy, 
and anyone who wants to publish virtual machine images in a way where 
tampering will be detected.</para>
    <para>vmcaster was designed with the realisation that users typically create new 
virtual machines images rarely but update them frequently. Vmcaster attempts 
to be the first of a new generation of image list publishers the minimise the 
data entry for updating images, with image lists.</para>
    <para>The tasks of updating an image and uploading a fresh signed image is now just 
two quiet short command line operations away. The aim is to make image and 
image list updates as painless as possible as these are the most common 
tasks.</para>
    <para>Internally the application uses a simple SQL database, SQLite for storing 
image lists and multiple back ends managing uploading of images / images lists 
using a facade pattern. This allows transfer protocol to be derived from the 
meta data of the image list and a configuration file, updates need much less 
effort.</para>
  </section>  



</chapter>
